so on Tuesday morning my cousin who's a
battalion chief for LA County Fire text
our family group chat and said don't go
to work today everyone needs to go to
the house start watering things down
start prepping there's a light up behind
you in the Palisades and there's a lot
of wind Anything could happen today
Chase and I jumped in the car and drove
from our place in Santa Monica back to
my family home that I've lived in since
I was born and my dad and my sister were
already there prepping Dory packed up
the dogs and got out and evacuated back
to our place and we just started
watering everything down we moved all of
the patio furniture away from the house
got our pool pump and our fire hose
ready to go and just started preparing
for the absolute worst we brought a
ladder up to the roof and just started
washing down all of the eaves all of the
vegetation running the sprinklers we
knew what was coming but we thought we
were going to be okay we just kept
thinking as long as the air drops can
stop the fire from Crossing this Ridge
we're going to be okay my cousin ended
up getting stationed nearby and he
stopped by and just told us to keep
doing what we were doing that he would
be in the area but probably wouldn't be
able to make it back for a while smoke
just kept getting thicker and thicker
and then once the fire jumped the ridge
we had tree sized tree branch sized
Embers hailing down on our house and
touching our roof touching our lawn
touching our vegetation the AstroTurf
lawn just melting it and we just kept
hosing it and doing our best to fight
the Embers our neighbors thought we were
crazy as they started evacuating and and
as things got more and more serious it
became harder and harder to take videos
and then like the worst thing we thought
could happen the fire ripped from that
Ridge all the way across the mountain to
the other Ridge we all just kept
fighting the Embers and watering it down
we knew it was just going to get worse
but we didn't know how bad the LA County
Fire Department was going up and down
the street telling everyone they needed
to evacuate now that the fires were
coming and then we started seeing the
first houses going up there were huge
booms in the distance the firing Embers
just kept raining down all around us and
our neighbors houses started catching
fire we just did our best to use our
garden hoses to just keep hosing them
down putting out the Embers wherever we
could we fired up our gas powered pool
pump and started using that there were
just huge plums of black smoke
everywhere huge booms of things
exploding from people's
homes all of the vegetation started
going up and then before we knew it the
fire had jumped the canyon in our NE
neighborhood and started lighting up
across the way we went and we're putting
out fires on the houses below us any
chance we had a minute to
breathe not really breathe because the
smoke was so thick we were all wearing
masks we didn't have goggles so we were
wearing sunglasses and then my sister
found these blue blocker glasses my
dad's truck caught on fire and she put
it out and somewhere in the middle of
this Chase broke the water M with the
fire hose and then macgyvered it back
together with a random piece of PVC and
saved us when the sun set it just was
the brightest most horrible night of our
life we watched our entire neighborhood
burn across the way and there was
nothing we could do but try to protect
the homes around us we'd lost all power
and utilities we still had water on our
side because we weren't in technically
in Malibu and we just that was really
what saved us we had no engines or
support on our side we couldn't figure
out why and was so sad to just see all
of the ashes and everything burning our
eyes lit up and got so infected we ended
up scaming for one pair of goggles
everything was burning we ended up
finding a couple of masks left over from
covid time we went to a neighbor's house
and their deck was completely on fire
one of their Gates Lo chasing and by the
time we were able to open the other gate
30ft Flames were erupting behind him
anytime things got too gnarly we had to
stop filming but we did our best to
capture things for our neighbors who we
love my dad had our emergency generator
power up so we were able to get a couple
more hours of light but it didn't do
much for us we had to be really careful
and conserve it and the next morning was
just horrible to wake up and know that
it wasn't even close to being over we
were just covered in thick ash and soot
and we started doing shifts every two
every hour and we started getting
reports about what it was looking like
and we decided to drive around the
neighborhood and see if there was anyone
who needed help and that's when we
noticed the true destruction that our
Beloved Community was facing we didn't
know what we were going to do but my dad
and I were trying to see if there was
anyone we could help in the neighborhood
and then we realized why we had no
engines on our side they were all over
here and they just couldn't do enough
the fire absolutely ripped all the way
across our Ridge through
TOA and it is just so devastating to see
what
happened to my neighborhood that I have
lived in since I was a baby
but we knew that it wasn't over yet
because the winds were still strong and
flare ups kept happening so all of these
areas that were smoldering kept burning
up we kept going with snorkel masks and
we were able to protect our eyes and
then in the middle of the night my
sister and I heard a boom we thought it
was a looter coming into the backyard
and I then I realized that there was a
fire on the hedge of our neighbor's
house I charged up the muddy Hill with
our garden hose and then their window
exploded from the Flames inside their
house and broke all over me I started
screaming for my dad and Chase and my
dad and I crawled a fire hose up the
muddy Hill as Chase fed a slack and then
luckily a fire engine was going by and
they stopped and were able to extinguish
the structure fire before it spread
through our whole street which is the
only part Still
Standing it was a long night and we
captured the fire department left we
just kept running around to our neighbor
houses trying to put out other fires and
they just told us to keep doing what we
were doing that there was any any small
flare up could be disastrous we thought
we were in the clear here because the
wind had died and the stars were out but
it was absolutely brutal the next
morning Chase went and used someone
else's pool pump to extinguish a fire on
their Hill the devastation is just
completely Brutal by this point we were
so worked and so run down from
everything that we had done
the toxic Flames that were coming out of
the house next door from their
construction materials were different
than the Wildfire Ash which was already
a thick glasslike sand we had to leave
so we ate some ice cream before we had
to throw it away said goodbye